Andrea M. Legleiter, MPS, BA

andreamlegleiter@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/andreamlegleiter/

www.andreamlegleiter.com

Full Stack Developer | Marketing & Business Generalist

Integrative web developer with entrepreneurial disposition who pairs capabilities in full-stack development with strong marketing, advertising, public relations, business, and client relations background. Expert in behavioral analytics, uncovering trends, patterns, and relationships, and using web-based platforms to bring discoveries to life.

K OV	Skills
Nev	SKIIIS

Front-End/Back-End Web Development Full Stack Web Development Mobile/Progressive Web Application Code Troubleshooting/Maintenance Consumer Experience Research/Strategy Human-Centered Web Design Project Management Client Advocacy Relationship Building Application Development User Experience (UX)
Critical Thinking
Collaborative Teamwork
Cross-Functional Collaboration
Verbal/Written Communication

Technical Profile

HTML5 | XML | CSS3 | SCSS | SASS | JavaScript | jQuery | Bootstrap | PHP | Java | SQL | Google Developer Tools | MVC | npm | node.js | TypeScript | Angular | Express | MongoDB | JSON | AJAX | PWA | RESTful | SPA | LAMP | XAMPP | MEAN | API | WordPress | Windows and Mac | Visual Studio Code | Android Studio | Notepad++ | Git | GitHub | Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator, Dreamweaver) | Microsoft Office 365 (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Publisher) | G-Suite (Docs, Sheets, Slides) | Apple iWork | Google Analytics | Google Developer Tools | Content Management System (CMS)

Education and Certifications

Master of Professional Studies (MPS) Web and Mobile Application Development - 4.0 GPA

May 2020

Fort Hays State University, Hays, KS

Dr. Bob Meier Outstanding Graduate Research Award | Fort Hays Honor Society Member

Core Coursework:

Human-Computer Interaction Front End Web Development I & II Back End Web Development I & II Database Design and Programming Mobile Web Development I & II Proseminar in Informatics Research Methods Capstone in Informatics

Graduate-Level Business Administration Courses - 30 credit hours

University of Colorado Denver, Denver, CO

Bachelor of Arts (BA) in Communication, Public Relations Emphasis

Fort Hays State University, Hays, KS

Magna cum laude

Associate of Arts (AA)

Seward County Community College, Liberal, KS

Summa cum laude | Female Academic Athlete of the Year Award

Certifications:

Full-Stack Web Developer Certification – Fort Hays State University, Hays, KS

Dec 2020

Publications and Research

Legleiter A.M., Caporusso N. (2020) Flat-Design Icon Sets: A Case for Universal Meanings? Proceedings of the 11th International Conference on Applied Human Factors and Ergonomics (AHFE 2020), July 16-20, 2020.

Experience

FULL-TIME PARENT | GRADUATE STUDENT | WEB DEVELOPER Self-Employed, Portland, ME & Lakeside, CT

2017 - Present

Oversee the care, upbringing, and development of a young child while working part-time on web development projects. Obtained a Master in Professional Studies in Web & Mobile Application Development and Full Stack Developer Certification.

• Presently developing websites for CQ Electrical Solutions of Boca Raton, FL and projects related to MPS program.

"Strength lies in differences, not in similarities." ~ Steven Covey

Andrea M. Legleiter, MPS, BA, Page 2

COMMUNITY RELATIONS ASSOCIATE

2016 - 2017

Hearth Management, Southbury, CT

Collaborated with Director of Community Relations in strategically achieving organization's sales, budget, marketing, advertising, and census goals. Established and nurtured professional and business referral relationships. Provided comprehensive sales and intake services to prospective residents, including tours, follow-ups, conversions, and move-ins.

• Achieved and maintained a 97% building occupancy rate.

INDEPENDENT CONTRACTOR - LAKEVIEW SUPPORTS

2008 - 2015

Imagine! Innovations, Westminster, CO (2008 – 2015)

Owned and operated a state-licensed therapeutic care residence that served adults and children with intellectual disabilities and behavioral challenges. Recruited, led, coached, and mentored a supporting team of alternate care providers.

• Reduced clients' target behaviors from multiple daily occurrences to 1-2 times per month and, for some clients, eliminated target behaviors by fully advocating for clients' needs, setting up predictive environments with clear expectations, and consistently applying behavioral management techniques.

NVCI (Non-Violent Crisis Intervention) INSTRUCTOR (2013 – 2015) Imagine! Innovations, Lafayette, CO

Taught monthly full certification and refresher NVCI classes. Maintained training records and ensured employee and independent contractor compliance with required certifications. Partnered with agency's Interdisciplinary Team to develop and revise safety control procedures, and review incident reports to ensure compliance with state and agency regulations.

• Consistently received positive feedback from students and supervisor by combining real-life experience with classroom instruction to connect student's learning with program techniques and reinforcing knowledge by empowering students to lead.

ADVOCACY COUNCIL MEMBER (2013 - 2014)

Imagine! Innovations, Lafayette, CO

Fulfilled a one-year voluntary term as member of organization's Advocacy Council, collaborating with other industry professionals in support of the organization's mission to empower individuals with intellectual disabilities to maintain full and independent lives.

• Learned that advocacy = action and that empathy is essential to becoming a true advocate.

THERAPEUTIC RESIDENTIAL COUNSELOR

2006 - 2008

TC's Community, Boulder, CO

Provided 1:1 safety supervision, personal care guidance, customized behavioral supports, and recreational services to a client with intellectual disabilities and behavioral challenges in support of individual plan benchmarks and goals.

 Learned the importance of building positive rapport with clients, celebrating small successes, staying calm in crises, and not taking negative matters personally.

ADVERTISING DIRECTOR MARKETING COORDINATOR

2005 - 2006

2005

D.R. Horton - Melody Series, Westminster, CO

Designed and delivered division-level advertising and marketing strategies for new-construction residential communities in metropolitan Colorado Springs, Denver, and Fort Collins, CO. Supervised a supporting 3-member marketing team.

• Saved ~\$38,000 in budgetary costs by renegotiating advertising contracts to align with online-based lead generation and through joint advertising efforts with other Colorado divisions.

MARKETING COORDINATOR

2004 - 2005

KB Home, Centennial, CO

Responsible for the coordination and management of internal and external marketing and advertising on behalf of the division's identity for new home communities in the metropolitan areas of Denver and Fort Collins, CO.

• Spearheaded the development of KB Home Colorado's first-ever homeowner's newsletter.